blackriflecoffee.com 2019-10-12

# Privacy Policy – Black Rifle Coffee Company

**_BRCC  PRIVA_** ** _CY POLICY_**

Effective Date: **July 15 th, 2019**

**Privacy Policy Scope**

Welcome!  An overview of this Black Rifle Coffee Company Privacy Policy is provided below.  To see the full text, navigate to the complete provisions.  This Privacy Policy applies to your use of any online services ( _e.g._ , website, software, or mobile app) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy, regardless of how you access or use it.  Visit <https://www.blackriflecoffee.com/pages/brcc-terms-and-conditions-july-15th-2019> to view our Terms of Use. 

**Overview**

**We have summarized some (but not all) of the main topics of this Privacy Policy below. The complete provisions, and not the headings or summaries govern.**

·       **Your Choices and Your CA Privacy Rights**

You have certain choices regarding information collection and communications options explained at Section 11, including:

\-- California residents have certain privacy rights detailed at Section 12;

\-- Although Black Rifle Coffee Company does not look for or respond to “do not track” signals, you can find information on tracking technologies at Section 1.B **.**

**\--** _About Ads and Tracking_ :  Learn about certain choice options regarding Tracking Technologies, including certain sharing of activities, location and/or cross-device usage for interest-based advertising at Section 11;

\-- Your options regarding accessing and changing certain of your Personal Information are available at Section 10;

\-- Your options regarding promotional communications are explained  at Section 11; and

\-- Children’s and minors’ privacy rights, and notice to parents of these rights, are explained at Section 9.

| 

·       **Use of Information**

The information Black Rifle Coffee Company collects is used for a variety of purposes as detailed in this Privacy Policy.  For example, your information helps Black Rifle Coffee Company provide and improve the Service, communicate with you, serve advertising and offers to you, and operate Black Rifle Coffee Company’s business. More at Section 2.

·       **Sharing of Information**

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company may share the information Black Rifle Coffee Company receives from or about you via the Service (or give others access to it), including your Personal Information, for a variety of purposes, as detailed in this Privacy Policy.  More at Section 3.  These include, without limitation:

§ to deliver and improve Black Rifle Coffee Company’s services;

§ for Black Rifle Coffee Company Affiliates **  **(defined below) purposes;

§ in connection with corporate transactions ( _e.g._ , merger or sale);

§ to display your posts or send your messages (More at Section 5);

§ in connection with your use of third-party services (More at Section 6); and

§ in connection with sweepstakes, contests and promotions (More at Section 4).

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company obtains your consent ( _e.g._ opt in, opt out), however, before knowingly sharing Personal Information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes.

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company may share your non-Personal Information, aggregate and/or de-identified information about you except as prohibited by applicable law.

·       **Questions and How to Contact Black Rifle Coffee Company**

For more information about Black Rifle Coffee Company’s privacy practices regarding the Service, read the full Privacy Policy.  You can also contact Black Rifle Coffee Company as set forth in Section 14 if you have questions or concerns.  
  
---|---  
  
·       **Collection of Information**

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company may ask you to provide Personal Information ( _e.g._ , name, address, e-mail, phone number, etc.), as well as other information ( _e.g._ , gender, interests, etc.), which may be required to access certain content, features, and functionality. More at Section 1.A.

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company and third parties may collect information from you automatically as you access the Service ( _e.g._ , information about the devices you use to access the Service and your usage activities).  More at Section 1.B.

\--This may include use of cookies and other technologies to keep track of your interactions with the Service, and to serve you with ads on third-party services, to offer you a more personalized and relevant experience.  More at Section 1.B.

\--The information Black Rifle Coffee Company receives via the Service may be combined with information Black Rifle Coffee Company receives from third parties and sources outside of the Service.  More at Section 1.C.

\-- Black Rifle Coffee Company’s policies and practices regarding Personal Information collected from children are explained at Section 9.   
  
**FULL BLACK RIFLE COFFEE COMPANY PRIVACY POLICY**

Thank you for visiting an online service ( _e.g._ , website or mobile app) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy ( **“Service”** ) owned or operated by Black Rifle Coffee Company, LLC (“ **Black Rifle Coffee Company** ” “ **we** ” “ **our** ” or “ **us** ”).   This Privacy Policy will provide you with information as to how Black Rifle Coffee Company collects, uses, and shares information about you, including the choices Black Rifle Coffee Company offers with respect to that information, and applies to your use of any Service, regardless of how you access or use it.  It does not apply to Black Rifle Coffee Company’s data collection activities offline or otherwise outside of the Service (unless otherwise stated below or at the time of collection). For certain Services, there may be additional notices about information practices and choices. Please read those additional privacy disclosures to understand how they apply to you.

By visiting or otherwise using the Service, you agree to the Service’s Terms of Use, available at <https://www.blackriflecoffee.com/pages/brcc-terms-and-conditions-july-15th-2019> and consent to Black Rifle Coffee Company’s data collection, use, and disclosure practices, and other activities as described in this Privacy Policy, and any additional privacy statements that may be posted on an applicable part of the Service.  If you do not agree and consent, please discontinue use of the Service, and uninstall Service downloads and applications.

## A.             Information about You that You Provide.

Black Rifle Coffee Company, and/or its Service Providers (defined below), may collect information you provide directly to Black Rifle Coffee Company and/or its Service Providers via the Service.  For example, Black Rifle Coffee Company collects information when you use or register for the Service, subscribe to notifications, post on the Service, participate in promotional activities, or communicate or transact through the Service.  In addition, when you interact with Third-Party Services (defined below), you may be able to provide information to those third parties.  For more information on Third-Party Services’ data collection and practices see Section 6.   For more information on Service Provider data collection and practices see Section 3.

Information Black Rifle Coffee Company, its Service Providers and/or Third-Party Services may collect may include: (1) personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you personally, such as your first and last name, e-mail address, phone number, address, and full payment account number ( **“Personal Information”** ); and (2) demographic information, such as your gender, age, zip code, interests, recent and upcoming purchases, and education, employment, and other background information when you submit a resume to the Service (“ **Demographic Information** ”).  Except to the extent required by applicable law, Demographic Information is **“non** - **Personal Information”** (i.e., data that is not Personal Information under this Privacy Policy).  In addition, Personal Information, including, without limitation, Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI (defined below), once **“De** - **identified”** (i.e., the removal or modification of the personally identifiable elements, or the extraction non-personally identifiable elements including through anonymization, pseudonymization, and/or hashing) is also non-Personal Information and may be used and shared without obligation to you, except as prohibited by applicable law.  However, we do not make assurances that De-identified data is not capable of re-identification. To the extent any non-Personal Information is combined by or on behalf of Black Rifle Coffee Company with Personal Information Black Rifle Coffee Company itself collects directly from you on the Service ( **“Black Rifle Coffee Company** - **Collected PI”** ), Black Rifle Coffee Company will treat the combined data as Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI under this Privacy Policy.

Black Rifle Coffee Company, its Service Providers, and/or Third-Party Services may also automatically collect certain information about you when you access or use the Service (“Usage Information”).  Usage Information may include IP address, device identifier, browser type, operating system, information about your use of the Service, and data regarding network connected hardware ( _e.g._ , computer or mobile device).  Except to the extent required by applicable law, or to the extent Usage Information is combined by or on behalf of Black Rifle Coffee Company with Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, Black Rifle Coffee Company does not consider Usage Information (including, without limitation, unique device identifiers) to be Personal Information or Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI.  For more information on Third-Party Services’ data collection and practices see Section 6.   For more information on Service Provider data collection and practices see Section 3.  For information on choices some of these third parties may offer you regarding automated data collection see Section 11.

The methods that may be used on the Service to collect Usage Information include:

  * **Log Information:** Log information is data about your use of the Service, such as IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamps, and related data, and may be stored in log files.

  * **Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** Cookies, web beacons (also known as “tracking pixels”), embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, device recognition technologies, in-app tracking methods and other tracking technologies now and hereafter developed (“ **Tracking Technologies** ”) may be used to collect information about interactions with the Service or e-mails, including information about your browsing and purchasing behavior.

  * **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s device, which may be session ID cookies or tracking cookies. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate the Service and expire when you close your browser. Tracking cookies remain longer and help in understanding how you use the Service, and enhance your user experience. Cookies may remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time. If you use your browser’s method of blocking or removing cookies, some but not all types of cookies may be deleted and/or blocked and as a result some features and functionalities of the Service may not work.  A Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file which may be placed on a device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your device.  HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage. Flash cookies and HTML5 cookies are locally stored on your device other than in the browser and browser settings won’t control them.  To identify certain types of local shared objects on your device and adjust your settings, please visit: [www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).  The Service may associate some or all of these types of cookies with your devices.

  * **Web Beacons (“Tracking Pixels”)**

Web beacons are small graphic images, also known as “Internet tags” or “clear gifs,” embedded in web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be used, without limitation, to count the number of visitors to the Service, to monitor how users navigate the Service, and to count content views.

  * **Embedded Scripts**

An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service. It is temporarily downloaded onto your computer from Black Rifle Coffee Company’s web server, or from a third party with which Black Rifle Coffee Company works, and is active only while you are connected to the Service, and deleted or deactivated thereafter.

  * **Location** - **identifying Technologies**

GPS (global positioning systems) software, geo-filtering and other location-aware technologies locate you (sometimes precisely), or make assumptions about your location, for purposes such as verifying your location and delivering or restricting content, including third party ads, based on your location.  If you have enabled GPS or use other location-based features on the Service, your device location may be tracked by us and third parties. Our store finder feature may access and use information about your device location (such as based on IP address or GPS, as applicable), or your account information, to suggest appropriate store locations.  Our Service content may be personalized based on various information we may have about you to try to provide you with more location-relevant content.

  * **Device Recognition Technologies _._**

Technologies, including application of statistical probability to data sets, as well as linking a common unique identifier to different device use (e.g., Facebook ID), which attempt to recognize or make assumptions about users and devices (e.g., that a user of multiple devices is the same user or household) (“ **Cross-device Data** ”).

  * **In** - **App Tracking Methods**

There are a variety of Tracking Technologies that may be included in mobile applications, and these are not browser-based like cookies and cannot be controlled by browser settings.  Some use device identifier, or other identifiers such as “Ad IDs” to associate app user activity to a particular app and to track user activity across apps and/or devices.

Some information about your use of the Service and certain third-party services may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services, and used by Black Rifle Coffee Company and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain third **-** party services.  See Section 11 regarding certain choices regarding these activities. 

Black Rifle Coffee Company is giving you notice of the Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them explained in Section 11 so that your consent to encountering them is meaningfully informed.

## C.             Information Black Rifle Coffee Company Collects From Other Sources.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may also obtain information about you from other sources, including Service Providers and Third-Party Services, and combine that with Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, except to the extent such data combined by or on behalf of Black Rifle Coffee Company with Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, this Privacy Policy is not intended to limit Black Rifle Coffee Company’s activities regarding such third-party-sourced, or non-Service-sourced, information (including Personal Information), and such data will only be treated as Black Rifle Coffee Company-collected PI to the extend it is combined with Black Rifle Coffee Company-collected PI. Black Rifle Coffee Company is not responsible or liable for the accuracy of the information provided by third parties or for third party policies or practices.

2.              HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE OBTAIN.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may use information about you, including Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI and other Personal Information, for any purposes not inconsistent with Black Rifle Coffee Company’s statements under this Privacy Policy, or otherwise made by us in writing at the point of collection, and not prohibited by applicable law, including, without limitation, the following:

  * Allow you to participate in the features we offer on the Service;

  * Facilitate, manage, personalize, and improve your online experience;

  * Process your registration, manage your account and/or upload your User Generated Content (“ **UGC** ”). (For more information on how UGC is treated under the Service’s Terms of Use see Section 9 of our Terms of Use.) For more on the public nature of UGC, see Section 5);

  * Transact with you, provide services or information you request, respond to your comments, questions and requests, serve you content and/or advertising, and send you notices;

  * Improve the Service and for any other internal business purposes;

  * Tailor our content, advertisements, and offers;

  * Fulfill other purposes disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information or otherwise where we are legally permitted or are required to do so;

  * Determine your location and manage digital content rights ( _g._ , territory restrictions); and

  * Prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm.

3.              information we share with third parties.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may share non-Personal Information, and Personal Information that is not deemed Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI hereunder (provided that Black Rifle Coffee Company is aware of no restrictions of Black Rifle Coffee Company’s use, if any), with third parties or other Black Rifle Coffee Company companies and their affiliates (the “ **Black Rifle Coffee Company Affiliates** ”) for any purpose. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, we and third parties may convert your Personal Information, including Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, to non-Personal Information, including without limitation through hashing it or substituting a unique identifier for the Personal Information and we and third parties may use and share that data as permitted by applicable law, including to match data attributes to and from other sources. Any such third party activities are subject to their privacy policies and practices.  Black Rifle Coffee Company’s sharing of Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI is, however, subject to the following:

  * _Marketing_ : Subject to your communications choices explained in Section 11.D, and the rights of California residents explained in Section 12, we may use your Personal Information to send you marketing communications.  Black Rifle Coffee Company will not share your Black Rifle Coffee Company **-** Collected PI with third parties, for their own direct marketing purposes, except in connection with Corporate Transactions (defined below) absent your consent (which may be by means of third party interaction described in the next bullet point).

  * _Your Disclosure or Consent_ : As more fully described in Section 5 (Information You Disclose Publicly or to Others) and Section 6 (Third-Party Content, Third-Party Services, Social Features, Advertising and Analytics), your activities on the Service may, by their nature, result in the sharing of your Black Rifle Coffee Company-collected Personal Information (as well as your other Personal Information and your non-Personal Information) with third parties and by engaging in these activities you consent to that and further sharing and disclosure to third parties.  Such third party data receipt and collection is subject to the privacy and business practices of that third party, not Black Rifle Coffee Company. 

Black Rifle Coffee Company may also share any information about you (including, without limitation, Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI) for any purposes not inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, or our written statements at the point of collection, and otherwise not prohibited by applicable law, including, without limitation:

  * Black Rifle Coffee Company’s agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers (collectively **“Service Providers”** ) may receive, or be given access to, your information, including, without limitation, Personal Information, Demographic Information, and Usage Information, in connection with their work on Black Rifle Coffee Company’s behalf, provided however, Black Rifle Coffee Company does not authorize its Service Providers to use Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI provided by Black Rifle Coffee Company to the Service Providers to send you direct marketing messages other than related to Black Rifle Coffee Company absent your consent. For more information on choices Service Providers may offer you see Section 11.

  * To comply with the law, law enforcement or other legal process, and, where permitted, in response to a government request; and

  * If Black Rifle Coffee Company believes your actions are inconsistent with Black Rifle Coffee Company’s terms of use, user agreements, applicable terms or policies, or to protect the rights, property, life, health, security and safety of Black Rifle Coffee Company, the Service or its users, or any third party.

In addition, Black Rifle Coffee Company may share your Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected Personal Information (as well as your other Personal Information and your non-Personal Information), in connection with or during negotiations of any proposed or actual financing of our business, or merger, purchase, sale, joint venture, or any other type of acquisition or business combination of all or any portion of Black Rifle Coffee Company assets, or transfer of all or a portion of Black Rifle Coffee Company’s business to another company, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding ( **“Corporate Transactions”** ).

**EEOC / Affirmative Action Reporting. _  _**In conjunction with laws and regulations enforced by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“ **EEOC** ”), the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (“ **OFCCP** ”) and similar state and local regulatory agencies, we may ask you to provide us with self-identifying information (such as veteran status, gender and ethnicity).  Providing such self-identifying information is voluntary, but if you do provide us with such information, we may submit that information, to the EEOC, the OFCCP and similar state and local regulatory agencies or otherwise use or disclose it for business-related purposes, including, without limitation, responding to information requests, fulfilling regulatory reporting requirements and defending against employment related complaints. **_ _**  

4.              Sweepstakes, Contests, and Promotions.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (each, a **“Promotion”** ), including Promotions jointly sponsored or offered by third parties, which may require submitting Personal Information.  If you voluntarily choose to enter a Promotion, your information, including Personal Information, may be disclosed to Black Rifle Coffee Company, co-sponsors, Service Providers, and other third parties, including for administrative purposes and as required by law ( _e.g._ , on a winners list). By entering, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that Promotion, which may include consent to additional or differing data practices from those contained in this Privacy Policy.  Please review those rules carefully.

5.              Information You Disclose Publicly or to Others.

The Service may permit you to post or submit UGC including, without limitation, written content, user profiles, audio or visual recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, or other content, including Personal Information.  If you choose to submit UGC to any public area of the Service, your UGC will be considered “public” and will be accessible by anyone, including Black Rifle Coffee Company.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, unless otherwise explicitly agreed by us, Personal Information included in UGC is not subject to Black Rifle Coffee Company’s usage or sharing limitations, or other obligations, regarding Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI or other Personal Information under this Privacy Policy or otherwise, and may be used and shared by Black Rifle Coffee Company and third parties to the fullest extent not prohibited by applicable law.  Black Rifle Coffee Company encourages you to exercise caution when making decisions about what you disclose in such public areas.  For more information on how UGC is treated under the Service’s Terms of Use see Section 9 of our Terms of Use **.**   California minors should see Section 9 regarding potential removal of certain UGC they have posted on the Service.

Additionally, the Service may offer you the option to send a communication to a friend or other contact. If so, Black Rifle Coffee Company relies on you to only send to people that have given you permission to do so.  The recipient’s Personal Information you provide ( _e.g._ , name, e-mail address) will be used to facilitate the communication, but not used by Black Rifle Coffee Company for any other marketing purpose unless Black Rifle Coffee Company obtains consent from that person.  Your contact information and message may be included in the communication. 

6.              Third-Party Content, Third-Party Services, SOCIAL FEATURES, ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS.

The Service may include hyperlinks to, or include on or in connection with, the Service (e.g., apps and plug-ins), websites, locations, platforms, applications or services operated by third parties ( **“Third** - **Party Service(s)”** ). These Third-Party Services may use their own cookies, web beacons, and other Tracking Technology to independently collect information about you and may solicit Personal Information from you. 

Certain functionalities on the Service permit interactions that you initiate between the Service and certain Third-Party Services, such as third party social networks ( **“Social Features”** ).  Examples of Social Features include: enabling you to send content such as contacts and photos between the Service and a Third-Party Service; “liking” or “sharing” Black Rifle Coffee Company’s content; logging in to the Service using your Third-Party Service account (e.g., using Facebook Connect to sign-in to the Service); and to otherwise connect the Service to a Third-Party Service (e.g., to pull or push information to or from the Service).  If you use Social Features, and potentially other Third-Party Services, information you post or provide access to may be publicly displayed on the Service (see Section 5) or by the Third-Party Service that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a third-party service that references the Service ( _e.g._ , by using a hashtag associated with Black Rifle Coffee Company or other Black Rifle Coffee Company Affiliates in a tweet or status update), your post may be used on or in connection with the Service or otherwise by Black Rifle Coffee Company and Black Rifle Coffee Company Affiliates.  Also, both Black Rifle Coffee Company and the third party may have access to certain information about you and your use of the Service and any Third-Party Service.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may engage and work with Service Providers and other third parties to serve advertisements on the Service and/or on third-party services.  Some of these ads may be tailored to your interest based on your browsing of the Service and elsewhere on the Internet, which may include use of precise location and/or Cross-device Data, sometimes referred to as “interest-based advertising” and “online behavioral advertising” ( **“Interest** - **based Advertising”** ), which may include sending you an ad on a third-party service after you have left the Service (i.e., “retargeting”).  

Black Rifle Coffee Company may use Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics or other Service Providers for analytics services.  These analytics services may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to help Black Rifle Coffee Company analyze Service users and how they use the Service.  Information generated by these services ( _e.g._ , your IP address and other Usage Information) may be transmitted to and stored by these Service Providers on servers in the U.S. (or elsewhere) and these Service Providers may use this information for purposes such as evaluating your use of the Service, compiling statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and providing other services relating to Service activity and other Internet usage. 

Except to the extent we combine information we receive from Service Providers, Third-Party Services, or other third parties with Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, in which case Black Rifle Coffee Company will treat the combined information as Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI under this Privacy Policy (see Section 1(c)), data obtained by Black Rifle Coffee Company from a third party, even in association with the Service, is not subject to Black Rifle Coffee Company’s limitations regarding Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI under this Privacy Policy, however such data remains subject to any restrictions imposed on Black Rifle Coffee Company by the third party, if any.  Otherwise, the information collected, stored, and shared by third parties remains subject to their privacy policies and practices, including whether they continue to share information with Black Rifle Coffee Company, the types of information shared, and your choices on what is visible to others on Third-Party Services. 

Black Rifle Coffee Company is not responsible for, and makes no representations regarding, the policies or business practices of any third parties, including, without limitation, analytics Service Providers and Third-Party Services associated with the Service, and encourages you to familiarize yourself with and consult their privacy policies and terms of use.  See Section 11 for more on certain choices offered by some third parties regarding their data collection and use, including regarding Interest-based Advertising and analytics.

7.              Data Security and MONITORING.

Black Rifle Coffee Company takes reasonable measures to protect Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI (excluding public UGC) from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Nevertheless, transmission via the Internet and online digital storage are not completely secure and Black Rifle Coffee Company does not guarantee the security of your information collected through the Service.

To help protect you and others, Black Rifle Coffee Company and its Service Providers may (but make no commitment to) monitor use of the Service, and may collect and use related information including Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI and other Personal Information for all purposes not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, including, without limitation, to identify fraudulent activities and transactions; prevent abuse of, and investigate and/or seek prosecution for, any potential threats to or misuse of the Service; ensure compliance with the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy; investigate violations of or enforce these documents; and otherwise to protect the rights and property of Black Rifle Coffee Company Affiliates, third parties, and other users.  Monitoring may result in the collection, recording, and analysis of online activity or communications through our Service.  If you do not consent to these conditions, you must discontinue your use of the Service.

8.              INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER.

Black Rifle Coffee Company is based in the U.S. and the information Black Rifle Coffee Company and its Service Providers collect is governed by U.S. law.  If you are accessing the Service from outside of the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the Service may be transferred to, processed, stored, and used in the U.S.  Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Service or provision of any information therefore constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the U.S. as set forth in this Privacy Policy.  

9.              Children’s Privacy.

The Service is intended for a general audience and not directed to children less than 13 years of age.

Black Rifle Coffee Company does not intend to collect personal information as defined by the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“ **COPPA** ”) ( **“Children’s Personal Information”** ) in a manner that is not permitted by COPPA.  If we obtain knowledge that we have collected Children’s Personal Information in a manner not permitted by COPPA, we will remove such data to the extent required by COPPA. 

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Service, and who posted content or information on the Service, can request removal by contacting Black Rifle Coffee Company at info@blackriflecoffee.com or at 355 Spencer Lane, San Antonio, TX 78201, (Attention: Chief Operations Officer), detailing where the content or information is posted and attesting that you posted it.  Black Rifle Coffee Company will then make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it so the minor cannot be individually identified to the extent required by applicable law. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third-parties may have republished or archived content by search engines and others that Black Rifle Coffee Company does not control.

10.           Accessing and Changing Information.

Black Rifle Coffee Company may provide web pages or other mechanisms allowing you to correct or update some of the Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, and potentially certain other information about you (e.g., profile and account information). You may contact us at customerservice@blackriflecoffee.com to request that we delete some of the Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI. Black Rifle Coffee Company will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in Black Rifle Coffee Company’s then-active databases as soon as practicable, but it is not always possible to completely change, remove or delete all of your information or public postings from Black Rifle Coffee Company’s databases (California minors see Section 9) and residual and/or cached data may remain archived thereafter.  Further, we reserve the right to retain data (a) as required by applicable law; and (b) for so long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the data is retained except to the extent prohibited by applicable law.

11.           choices:  TRACKING AND Communications OPTIONS.

A.             Tracking Technologies Generally. Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings.  Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately.  Also, tools from commercial browsers may not be effective with regard to Flash cookies (also known as locally shared objects), HTML5 cookies, or other Tracking Technologies.  For information on disabling Flash cookies, go to Adobe’s website <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-third-party-local-shared.html>.  Please be aware that if you disable or remove these technologies, some parts of the Service may not work and that when you revisit the Service your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations. 

Some App-related Tracking Technologies in connection with non-browser usage ( _e.g._ , most functionality of a mobile app) can only be disabled by uninstalling the app.  To uninstall an app, follow the instructions from your operating system or handset manufacturer.  Apple and Google mobile device settings have settings to limit ad tracking, and other tracking, but these may not be completely effective.

Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit.  Note, however, there is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context.  Like many online services, Black Rifle Coffee Company currently does not alter Black Rifle Coffee Company’s practices when Black Rifle Coffee Company receives a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you can visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/), but Black Rifle Coffee Company is not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this third party information.  Some third parties, however, may offer you choices regarding their Tracking Technologies. One way to potentially identify cookies on our web site is to add the free Ghostery plug-in to your browser ( ** _www.ghostery.com_** ), which according to Ghostery will display for you traditional, browser-based cookies associated with the web sites (but not mobile apps) you visit and privacy and opt-out policies and options of the parties operating those cookies.  Black Rifle Coffee Company is not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this tool or third party choice notices or mechanisms.   For specific information on some of the choice options offered by third party analytics and advertising providers, see the next section.

B.             Analytics and Advertising Tracking Technologies. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.  You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Adobe Analytics by going to http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html under the section labeled “Tell our customers not to measure your use of their web sites or tailor their online ads for you.”

You may choose whether to receive some Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt-outs.  Some of the advertisers and Service Providers that perform advertising-related services for us and third parties may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“ **DAA** ”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising.  To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, including use of Cross-device Data for serving ads, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, and <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices> for information on the DAA’s opt-out program specifically for mobile apps (including use of precise location for third party ads).  Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt-out options for their members, see http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/.  Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads.  Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads ( _e.g._ , from other ad networks).  Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit these opt-out webpages, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different device or web browser or use a non-browser-based method of access ( _e.g._ , mobile app), your NAI / DAA browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective.  Black Rifle Coffee Company supports the ad industry’s **_2009 Self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising_ (**https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf ** _)_** and expects that ad networks Black Rifle Coffee Company directly engages to serve you Interest-based Advertising will do so as well, though Black Rifle Coffee Company cannot guaranty their compliance. Black Rifle Coffee Company is not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs. 

In addition, we may serve ads on third-party services that are targeted to reach people on those services that are also identified on one of more of our data bases ( **“Matched List Ads”** ).  This is done by using Tracking Technologies or by matching common factors between our data bases and the data bases of the third-party services.  For instance, we may use such ad services offered by Facebook or Twitter and other Third-Party Services.  We are not responsible for these Third-Party Services, including without limitation their security of the data.  If we use Facebook to serve Matched List Ads on Facebook services, you should be able to hover over the box in the right corner of such a Facebook ad, or go to your account settings, and find out what options Facebook offers you to control such ads.  If we use Twitter Matched List Ads, you should be able to review your ad options in account settings on Twitter. We are not responsible for such third parties’ failure to comply with your or our opt-out instructions, they may not give us notice of opt-outs to our ads that you give to them, and they may change their options without notice to us or you.

C.             Mobile Apps. With respect to Black Rifle Coffee Company’s mobile apps (“apps”), you can stop all collection of data generated by use of the app by uninstalling the app.  Also, you may be able to exercise specific privacy choices, such as enabling or disabling certain features (e.g., location-based services, push notifications, accessing calendar/contacts/photos, etc.), by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device and/or the app’s settings. Beware that if GPS precise location services are disabled, other means of establishing or estimating location (e.g., connecting to or proximity to wi-fi, Bluetooth, beacons, or our networks) may persist.  To learn more about how you can exercise choices regarding certain choices regarding precise location tracking for Interest-based Advertising, and mobile app Interest-based Advertising more generally, see the prior section regarding the DAA’s mobile Interest-based Advertising choices.

D.             Communications. You can opt out of receiving certain promotional communications (emails or text messaging) from Black Rifle Coffee Company at any time by (i) for promotional e-mails, following the instructions provided in emails to click on the unsubscribe link, or if available by changing your communication preferences by logging onto your account; (ii) for text messages, following the instructions provided in text messages from Black Rifle Coffee Company to text the word, “STOP”; and (iii) for app push notifications turn off push notifications on the settings of your device and/or the app, as applicable.  Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address or phone number used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions.  If you opt-out of only certain communications, other subscription communications may continue.  Even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, Black Rifle Coffee Company may, subject to applicable law, continue to send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or Black Rifle Coffee Company’s ongoing business relations.  Except in connection with Corporate Transactions, to prospectively opt-out of our sharing of your Company-Collected PI, contact Black Rifle Coffee Company at info@blackriflecoffee.com or at 355 Spencer Lane, San Antonio, TX 78201.

  1. **Cross-Device Data.** To learn more about how you can exercise choices regarding certain choices regarding Cross-device data for Interest-based Advertising, see the prior section regarding the DAA’s Interest-based Advertising choices. 

12.       Your California Privacy Rights.

We do not share personal information as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine The Light law”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes absent your consent. If you are a California resident, you may request information about our compliance with the Shine the Light law by contacting Black Rifle Coffee Company by sending a letter to us at 355 Spencer Lane, San Antonio, TX 78201, (Attention: Chief Operations Officer) or by emailing us at info@blackriflecoffee.com. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code.  Please note that Black Rifle Coffee Company is only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided e-mail address or mail address.

California minors should see “Children’s Privacy” Section 9 regarding removal of certain content they have posted. 

13.       Changes to This Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy prospectively effective upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy and your use of our Service indicates your consent to the privacy policy posted at the time of use.  However, we will not treat your previously collected Black Rifle Coffee Company-Collected PI, to the extent it is not collected under the new privacy policy, in a manner materially different than represented at the time it was collected without your consent. If you have a subscription to a Service, materials changes to tthe Privacy Policy will only become effective with respect to the aspect of that subscription Service at the end of the then current term unless you otherwise consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.

14.       Contact Black Rifle Coffee Company.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact Black Rifle Coffee Company at info@blackriflecoffee.com or at 355 Spencer Lane, San Antonio, TX 78201, (Attention: Chief Operations Officer).

//End Privacy Policy//

_©_ _Black Rifle Coffee Company, LLC 2019.   All Rights Reserved._
